

# Mike Grace SOFTWARE ENGINEER



mikegrace.tech



mike@mikegrace.tech



440-829-5501



/mikeegrace



/TravelFiend

#### **BACKGROUND & PROFILE**

Full-Stack software engineer experienced in building and deploying apps using React, React Native, and both relational and document databases. Enjoys finding creative ways of solving intricate problems and continuing to experiment and implement new technologies. Currently working with D3, Typescript, Sass, AWS, and Python!

#### **TECH KNOWLEDGE**

Languages
Javascript
HTML
CSS

Frontend
React / Redux
React Native
React Hooks

Backend Node.js Express

<u>Database</u> PostgreSQL MongoDB Mongoose

Tools
Github
Postman
Heroku
Netlify
TravisCl
VS Code

Testing
Jest
QUnit
Enzyme

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Lifetime Optimization Inc.

Full-Stack Software Engineer

March 2020 – Present GOOGLE PLAY // APPLE STORE

- Collaborated remotely with one other dev to launch a mobile app and accompanying web app/backend, playing the role of architect, developer and maintenance. Our app, NMConnect, gives users access to health and wellness resources.
- Helped save a \$1.5 million contract with the State of New Mexico, as well as helping to secure an additional \$200K of funding.

## **Ardmore Logistics**

March 2019 - August 2019

**Operations Coordinator** 

- Responsible for booking and tracking carriers for energy industry shipments
- Helped in improving the UX for the company's in-house GUI

## **Sykes Enterprises**

May 2013 - July 2018

**IT Logistics Specialist** 

- Performed system inspections with detailed inspection notes
- Helped to reduce preparation and deployment time by organizing the inventory and streamlining workflow for increased productivity

#### **PROJECTS**

## CovrLettr

SITE // GITHUB

React - MongoDB - Mongoose - Express - Jest - NodeJS - JWT - BCryptJS

A cover letter generator that takes user input for a series of questions and creates up to a million unique cover letters and returns the version with the highest sentiment score. In this four-developer, one-week sprint, I was responsible for creating the majority of the backend including the identifier replacement algorithm, as well as the front-end functionality, excluding styling.

# KIT (Keep in Touch)

SITE // GITHUB

React - Redux - Express - Node.js - MongoDB - Mongoose - Passport - Jest

KIT is a tool for setting and tracking communication goals. Users enter contacts and select how frequently they'd like to contact each person. The app will then send push notification reminders based on user settings. Another one week sprint with five developers in which I helped build the backend (including routes and models), style the frontend and implement Redux. I also built out a sorting function based on how close a contact is getting to their KIT deadline.

## **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

## Alchemy Code Lab

Full-Stack Software Engineering 2020

# Ohio University

BFA in Printmaking 2011